healthypages.net 2006-06-15

# HealthyPages - Complementary health, natural therapies and alternative medicine

**PRIVACY POLICY**

Touch IT Solutions is the sole owner of the information collected on healthypages.co.uk.   
Touch IT Solutions collects information from our users at several different points on our Web site.

**Registration**  
In order to use this Web site, a user must first complete the registration form. During registration a user is required to give contact information (such as name and email address). We use this information to contact the user about services on our site for which he has expressed interest. 

**Orders**  
We request information from the user on our order form. A user must provide contact information (such as name, email, and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customer’s orders. If we have trouble processing an order, the information is used to contact the user.

**Information Use**  
We do not sell or pass on to any other companies or individuals any information that is collected through our website, 

**Profile**  
We store information that we collect through cookies, log files A profile is stored information that we keep on individual users that details their viewing preferences. Consequently, collected information is tied to the users personally identifiable information to provide offers and improve the content of the site for the user. This profile is used to tailor a user’s visit to our Web site, and to direct pertinent marketing promotions to them. We do not share your profile with other third parties.

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s computer tied to information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once users close the browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user’s hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions.

By setting a cookie on our site, users would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If users reject the cookie, they may still use our site. The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas of our site. 

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by healthypages.co.uk only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. 

How to control your cookies

Netscape 6.0:  
On your Task Bar, click:   
Edit, then   
Preferences   
Click on Advanced   
Click on Cookies 

Internet Explorer 6.0:   
Choose Tools, then   
Internet Options   
Click the Privacy Tab   
Click on Custom Level   
Click on the 'Advanced' button   
Check the 'override automatic cookie handing' box and select Accept, Block or Prompt for action as appropriate. 

Internet Explorer 5.0 or 5.5:   
Choose Tools, then   
Internet Options   
Click the Security tab   
Click on Custom Level   
Scroll down to the sixth option to see how cookies are handled by IE5 and change to Accept, Disable, or Prompt for action as appropriate. 

**Log Files**  
Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. 

**Communications from the Site**

**Special Offers and Updates**  
We send all new members a welcoming email to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals from our sponsors, and a weekly newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections.

**Newsletter**  
If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. Out of respect for our users privacy we provide a way to opt-out of these communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections.

**Service Announcements**  
On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature. 

**Customer Service**  
We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account we reply via email or phone, in accordance with the users wishes.

**Sharing**  
**Legal Disclaimer**  
Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site.

**Business Transitions**  
In the event healthypages.co.uk goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users’ personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. 

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications by replying to unsubscribe in the subject line in the email or email us at: info@healthypages.net We also offer an opt-out mechanism on the Newsletter Subscriptions/management page or the user may contact us at: Tel: +44 1206 500999 Email: info@healthypages.net or by post to:  
Healthypages, Touch IT Solutions, First Floor Offices, 29 Crouch Street, Colchester, Essex  CO3 3EN. UK.

**Links**  
This Web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, Touch IT Solutions, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

**Surveys & Competitions**  
From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or competitions. Participation in these surveys or competitions is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as Postcodes). Contact information will be used (shared with the competitions [survey] sponsors to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. Users’ personally identifiable information is not shared with third parties unless we give prior notice and choice. 

**Tell-A-Friend**  
If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask them for the friend’s name and email address. Healthypages.co.uk will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site. Healthypages.co.uk does not store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. 

**Public Discussion Forums**  
Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online \- for example on message boards, through e-mail, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, by posting personal information online that is publicly accessible, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.

**Security**  
This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users’ information. When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, their information is protected both online and off-line.

When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when users are just ‘surfing’. No Credit card details are stored on our servers for the customers safety.

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Our employees must use password-protected screen-savers when they leave their desk. When they return, they must re-enter their password to re-gain access to user information. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices.

If users have any questions about the security at our Web site, users can send an email to admin@healthypages.net

**Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information**  
If a user’s personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users’ personally identifiable information. This can usually be done at the member information page for the particular service that they are wanting to update/delete or by emailing our Customer Support at info@healthypages.net or by: Tel: +44 1206 500999 or by post to: Healthypages, Touch IT Solutions, PO Box 3718, Fordham Heath, Colchester, Essex CO3 9UB. UK.

**Notification of Changes**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

If, however, we are going to use users’ personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users via email

**Contact Information**  
If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at:

Phone: 44 1206 500999  
Fax: 44 1206 500888  
Email: info@healthypages.co.uk  
Postal Address: Healthypages, Touch IT Solutions, First Floor Offices, 29 Crouch Street, Colchester, Essex  CO3 3EN. UK.  
Web site URL: http://www.healthypages.co.uk
